《貓鼠游戲》前情提要
Previously on "White Collar"...
粉紅豹
Pink Panthers,
世界上最危險的盜竊團伙
most dangerous gang of thieves in the world.
他叫艾倫·伍德福德
This is Alan Woodford,
艾倫·伍德福德
長期以來被認為是該團伙的頭目
long suspected to be the leader of the group.
沒有任何一個執法機構得到過抓住他們的一絲機會
No law enforcement agency has ever come close to catching them.
尼爾打算潛入這個團伙
Neal plans to infiltrate the gang.
我們有麻煩了  馬修·凱勒
We have a problem: Matthew Keller.
他加入了粉紅豹
He's running with the Panthers.
這不可能
That's impossible.
凱勒被關在俄羅斯的監獄里
Keller's locked away in a Russian prison.
小伊懷孕了
El's pregnant.
敬未來
To the future.
你為國際刑警組織工作多久了
How long you been working for Interpol?
瞧  我跟你得到了一樣的協議
See, I got the same deal that you do.
知道他們管這個叫什么嗎
You know what they call this?
玉石俱焚
Mutually assured destruction.
美蘇冷戰中囤積核武器制約對方  被稱為Mutually assured destruction(MAD瘋子計劃)
你有我的把柄  我也有你的
You got something on me. I got something on you.
國際刑警不可信  尼爾
Interpol is not to be trusted, Neal.
所有機構你都這么說
You say that about every institution--
航空局  善待動物組織  甚至公共廣播電臺
NASA, PETA, even NPR.
他們都是極權主義的邪教
They're all totalitarian cults.
別忘記二戰時期國際刑警是由納粹操控的
Lest we forget the Nazis ran Interpol during World War II.
好了  納粹德國沒有操控凱勒的釋放
Okay, the S.S. is not behind Keller's release.
好  所以國際刑警不壞  他們只是蠢
Okay, so Interpol isn't evil. They're simply stupid.
不能跟凱勒這種人做交易
You don't make a deal with someone like Keller.
好消息是我們現在知道了凱勒的目的
But the good news is that now we know what Keller's up to.
我們有了籌碼
We have leverage.
他也有
As does he.
你知道玉石俱焚中
You do realize that mutually assured destruction
還是有"焚"字的  對吧
still contains the word "destruction," right?
別跟我說這里面有只貓
Please tell me there isn't a cat in there.
我能看看嗎
May I?
如果我在它腿上扎一針
If I poke its leg with a pin,
彼得會有感覺嗎
does Peter feel it?
這是個猴寶寶
It's a Sarubobo,
日本送給準媽媽的幸運符
Japanese good luck amulet for expecting mothers.
這是送...一個朋友的
It's for a friend.
我知道伊麗莎白懷孕了  蚊子
I know that Elizabeth's pregnant, Moz.
那你應該也知道
Oh, you should also know
我會當伊麗莎白的臨產特護
that I'm gonna be Elizabeth's doula.
-彼得沒提這事  -他不知道
- Peter left that part out. - He doesn't know.
我還沒跟他提這項服務
I haven't offered my services yet.
我敢肯定他會很激動
I'm sure he'll be thrilled.
是粉紅豹
It's the Pink Panthers.
兩個小時后我要跟他們見面
I have a meeting in a couple hours.
我覺得我的禮物可以晚點送
Oh, I suppose my gift-giving can wait.
僅限會員
It's members only.
時機成熟我會帶你入會的
Look, I'll bring you in when the timing's right.
我得去趟聯調局
I got to get to the F.B.I.
見完他們我給你打電話
I'll call you after the meeting's over.
馬修·凱勒在為國際刑警做線人
Matthew Keller is working as a criminal informant for Interpol.
我聯系過他們
I've reached out to them,
但他們聲稱完全不知道這個行動
But they've denied any knowledge of the operation.
我們深入調查過
Well, we did some digging.
有可能國際刑警使用了無線射頻的追蹤芯片
Chances are Interpol are using an R.F.I.D tracking chip.
如果能接近凱勒  我們就能定位他的信號
If we get close to Keller, we can pinpoint his signal
然后追蹤他
and track him too.
所有粉紅豹成員到達時都要接受掃描
All the members of the Panthers are scanned on arrival.
他從未觸發過警報
He's never set it off.
不  他們一定是每次開/關芯片
No, they must be switching the chip on and off.
也就是說會有人負責開關
Which means there's someone at the switch.
凱勒有個負責人
Keller has a handler.
會面時凱勒行動自由
And if Keller is off leash,
說明這個負責人一定就在附近
it means he must be close by.
我們會在會面地點附近的幾條街
We'll set up surveillance within a few blocks
設下監控
of the meet location,
看看還有誰在監視
see who else is watching.
很好  你跟粉紅豹碰面的時候
Excellent. While you're meeting the Panthers,
我們會跟那個蠢到放凱勒出來的人
we'll say hi to whoever was dumb enough
好好打個招呼
to let Keller out of prison.
別麻煩了
Don't bother.
攝像頭都豎好了
We're already set up.
對所有人啟用面部識別并跟國際刑警的數據庫
It's gonna take a while to run facial recognition on everyone
交叉對比  這得花不少時間
and crosscheck Interpol's database.
如果凱勒的負責人是臥底
If Keller's handler is undercover,
他就不會在數據庫里
he won't be in it.
我們用老辦法
We'll do it the old-fashioned way.
先拍照  之后再對比
Shoot pictures now, match them up later.
沒錯
Exactly.
如果下次跟蹤凱勒時再看到其中哪個人
If we see any of these people next time we track Keller,
我們就找到他的負責人了
we'll have his handler.
在這地方集合可不好撤離
Not a very discrete location for a gathering.
因為集合的只有你和我
It's because it's just you and me.
什么意思  伍德福德呢
What are you talking about? Where's Woodford?
他出城談生意去了
He's out of town on business.
跟粉紅豹的人一起嗎
With the Panthers?
怎么  難道他會告訴我嗎
What, like he told me?
但他走之前  給我們下了行動令
But before he left, he gave us marching orders.
我們
Us?
我們要一起行動  卡夫瑞
We're working together, Caffrey,
就跟過去一樣
just like old times.
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
■
翻譯：H小欠  灰灰是菇涼  陳小圈  阿包
翻譯：CS小明漫畫家  Liv 王小麥
■
時間軸：JimmyBeck  阿包  今   校對：灰灰是菇涼  王小麥
貓鼠游戲
第六季 第三集
■
后期&總監：灰灰是菇涼
貓鼠游戲
第六季 第三集
尼爾和凱勒已經走了
Neal and Keller are leaving already.
沒時間收集照片了
No time to collect photographs.
我們只能憑記憶了
We'll have to do it by memory.
伍德福德想讓我們混進這個叫阿特拉斯科技的公司
So Woodford wants us to break into this company called Atlas Tech.
辦公室里面有個保險庫
Now, inside the office, there's a vault.
保險庫里面有份電子文件叫"出埃及記"
Inside that vault is a digital file named "Exodus."
文件里面是什么
What's in the file?
這不用我們操心
It's not our concern,
我們得神不知鬼不覺地
but we got to make a copy of that file
復制那份文件
without anybody knowing.
好啊  我能搞定
Yeah. I can take this.
我完工了打電話給你
I'll call you when I'm done.
別這樣
Come on, huh?
一起行動這個主意難道沒讓你有一絲興奮嗎
Doesn't the idea of working together give you a little tingle?
沒  沒有
No, it doesn't.
那太遺憾了  因為這是伍德福德的命令
That's too bad 'cause it's Woodford's orders,
所以如果你還想得到自由
so if you want this freedom thing,
那你就甩不掉我了
you're stuck with me.
你有辦法進去嗎
Do you have a way in?
說實話  還真有
As a matter of fact, I do.
我想  為了慶祝咱倆再聚首
I figured in honor of our reunion
我們用經典那一招
we'd go with a classic.
女士正在等
Lady awaits.
她叫艾米·哈里斯
Her name is Amy Harris.
她是阿特拉斯科技執行總裁的行政助理
She's the executive assistant to the CEO of Atlas Tech,
總裁名叫哈羅德·格蘭特
a guy by the name of Harold Grant.
她已經在那里工作了六年
She's been working there for six years,
所以深得老板信任
so we know she's got her boss's trust.
也就是說她有權限進保險庫
Which means she has access to the vault.
沒錯
Exactly.
接下來三天  這位大老板都在外地
And the big boss, he's out of town for the next 72 hours.
取得她信任的時間不多了
That's a tight window to gain her confidence.
所以他們才挑了最強的人
Well, that's why they chose the best.
學著點
Watch and learn.
不  等等  稍微等一下  好嗎
No, wait, just hold on a second, all right?
她笑得很自然  會跟人眼神接觸
She smiles easily, makes eye contact.
她是個很好的人
She's a good person.
那就是說她很容易搞定
That makes her an easy mark.
不  那就是說你沒機會的
No, that means you don't have a shot.
那就讓我看看你是怎么搞定的  大師
Well, then show me how it's done then, maestro.
好吧
Okay.
我們不需要把她牽扯進來
We don't need to involve her in this.
我們去大樓
Let's go back to the building,
想個別的辦法
Find another way.
我已經考察過了
I already staked it out.
這是唯一的辦法
This is the only way.
你說了算  卡夫瑞
It's your call, Caffrey.
你上還是我上
It's either you or me.
這是球莖甘藍
It's a kohlrabi.
抱歉你說什么
I'm sorry?
你拿著的那個  嘗起來像甜的卷心菜
What you're holding, it's like a sweet cabbage.
拿它做沙拉
It's great in a salad
拌一點點海鹽和橄欖油  味道很好
with a little sea salt and olive oil,
或者你也可以剝皮
or you can peel away the skin
把它當蘋果吃
and eat it like an apple.
這個蘋果挺奇怪的
That's one weird apple.
我來自美國的糧倉愛達荷州
I'm from the nation's breadbasket.
我們那兒種很多東西  就是沒種過這個
We grow a lot of things, but nothing like this.
你來紐約幾年了
How long you been in New York?
六年了
Six years.
差不多算是本地人了
Ah, you're practically a native.
我愛這個城市的一切
I love everything about this city,
就連這的蔬菜也是
even its vegetables.
但我父母堅持說愛荷華才是我真正的家
But my parents keep insisting that Iowa's my real home.
父母都這樣
Oh, they're parents, right?
是啊
Right.
給我這個好嗎
Can I get this?
給我一打佛手瓜  一打球莖甘藍
A dozen chayote squash, another dozen kohlrabi,
再來三磅豆薯
And, uh, three pounds of jicama.
怎么  我餓死了
What? I'm really hungry.
有看到眼熟的嗎
Anyone look familiar?
還沒
Not yet.
我一直在找歐洲版的你
I keep looking for Euro-Peter--
光鮮西裝窄領帶  成天戴著副墨鏡
Slick suit, skinny tie, Bono glasses.
我要是戴墨鏡多帥的
I could pull off Bono glasses.
我倒想看看呢
I would love to see you try.
他肯定就在這附近
He's gotta be around here somewhere.
咖啡桌那邊的那個人
Ooh, that guy over there at the cafe,
我之前看到過他
I think I saw him before.
看起來很眼熟
Looks familiar.
需要后援嗎
You want backup?
沒事
I'll be fine.
你盯著點卡夫瑞
Keep an eye on Caffrey.
你是廚師  太棒了
A chef? That's amazing.
悠著點
Easy.
悠著點  要是個有錢的大廚才好呢  但是
Easy, it would be amazing if I were a rich chef, but--
是的  但是你熱愛你的職業
Yes, but you're doing what you love.
這倒是
Yeah.
從你說話的口氣就能聽出來
I can hear it in your voice.
沒多少人可以做自己喜歡做的事
Not many people get to do that.
你呢
What about you?
我是個助理
I'm an assistant.
這樣啊
All right.
是的
Yeah.
很能激發工作熱情的活  對吧
Total passion job, right?
如果那是你熱愛的職業的話
Well, if it leads to doing what you love,
那么是的
then yes.
也許吧
Yeah, I guess.
敬熱情
To passion.
送給你
It's for you.
謝謝
Thank you.
和你聊天很開心
It was good talking to you.
我也是
You too.
美女
Hey, beautiful.
我是外地來的
So I'm visiting from out of town.
給我做個導游吧
I could use a tour guide.
對不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
我幫不了你
I can't help you.
怎么了  你看起來人很好
What's the matter? You seem like a nice girl, huh?
不愿意幫人忙嘛
Don't want to help a guy out?
親愛的  他在糾纏你嗎
Honey, is he bothering you?
沒有  沒事
No, it's okay.
好吧
All right.
我沒有搞清楚情況  我向你道歉
I misread the situation. I apologize.
是該道歉
I'd say so.
我說過抱歉了
I just said I'm sorry.
你應該感到抱歉
You should be.
-抱歉  -謝謝
- Sorry. - Thank you.
別謝我
No.
你不必幫我的
You didn't have to do that.
不好意思
Sorry.
不  沒關系
No, no, it's no problem.
我想這是擺脫那種流氓糾纏的最快方法了
I just thought that was the fastest way to get rid of that jerk.
是的  他就是我剛搬來這里時
Yeah, he's--he's the kind of guy that my friends
朋友們提醒我要提防的那種人
warned me about when I first moved here.
等不及要跟她們說說你了
Wait until I tell them about you.
為了你的安全
You know, just to be safe,
不如我送你去你要去的地方吧
why don't I walk you to where you're going?
只有我和一袋豆薯
It's just me and some jicama.
-你可以相信我  -你都已經是我的男朋友了
- You can trust me. - I mean, apparently you are my boyfriend.
這倒是頭一回
Well, that's a first
我從來沒交過不知道名字的女朋友
because I've never had a girlfriend whose name I didn't know.
我叫艾米
I'm Amy.
我是尼爾
Neal.
-很高興認識你  尼爾  -很高興認識你
- Nice to meet you, Neal. - Nice to meet you.
就算沒有好人把壞人放出來
It's hard enough putting the bad guys in prison
要把他們抓進去已經很難了
without the good guys letting them out.
這話同樣適用于你自己  博爾克探員
The same could be said for you, Agent Burke.
我有預感很快就會見到你
I had the feeling I'd see you soon.
是嗎
Did you?
我還以為會更快些
I thought it would be sooner.
盧克·雷諾
Luc Renaud.
你能主動聯系我的話我們就能更早見面了
It would have been sooner had you reached out to me.
那樣對我沒什么好處
That would not have been in my best interests.
你不想鏟除粉紅豹嗎
You don't want to take down the Pink Panthers?
想啊
Oh, I do.
我是不想被聯調局偷走我的案子
What I do not want is the F.B.I trying to steal my case.
我不會的
I wouldn't do that.
你覺得很好笑嗎
That's funny to you?
我只想逮捕他們
All I care about is arresting them.
到了
Well, here I am.
明天要一起吃午餐嗎
How about lunch tomorrow?
我的工作不允許我因為吃飯
My job doesn't allow me to leave the desk
之類的瑣事離開辦公桌
for pesky things like eating.
還有這種事
What are you talking about?
他們就給了我五分鐘去農貿市場
I barely get five minutes for the farmer's market.
晚餐怎么樣
Dinner?
我來燒菜
I'll cook.
這是我的電話號碼
So here's my number.
名片  好正式
Oh, a card, very official.
再次謝謝你
Thank you again.
不用謝
You're welcome.
別工作得太累了
Don't work too hard.
待會兒見
See you soon.
Yes, I'll see you soon.
再見
Bye.
不用謝我
You're welcome.
我已經控制住局面了
I had it under control.
是嗎  隨你怎么說
Yeah, whatever.
我把她放在盤子上送到你嘴前了
I handed her to you on a platter.
現在你是她的英雄了
I mean, now you're her hero.
我們一起干了那么多活
You know, in all that time working together,
我們居然從來沒一起演過這出
I can't believe we never pulled that con.
不能演
I can.
光看你的"表演"就蛋疼
Just watching your side of it is physically painful.
但很有效啊
But effective.
我們得去個地方
We have somewhere to be.
瞧瞧這
Aw, look at this,
幸福的一家
one big happy family.
凱勒  我們四個得談談
Keller, the four of us need to talk.
很高興再見到你  小博
It's good to see you again, Burkie.
你老婆怎么樣
How's the wife?
閉嘴  馬修
Shut your mouth, Matthew.
大家都坐下吧
Why don't we all sit down?
我們四個有著共同的目標
The four of us have the same goal,
因此我們必須齊心協力
so we need to be working together.
不能給對方使絆子
We can't be tripping over each other.
我同意
I agree.
你把尼爾給我  在一旁看著就行
Give me Neal and step aside.
布萊克·愛德華茲《粉紅豹》系列電影中的人物
做夢去吧  克魯索警督
Oh, dream on, Inspector Clouseau.
尼爾是我的線人
Neal is my C.I.
對  顯然你把他控制得很好
Yes, one that you clearly can control.
行了  客套話可以結束了
All right, all right, politeness is over.
尼爾為我工作
Neal works for me.
要么你配合我要么拉倒
You work with me or you're out.
這是在美國
This is the United States.
這是聯調局的地盤
This is F.B.I turf,
你也知道你不可能憑一己之力拿下這些人
and you know that you can't take these guys down by yourself.
你低估我了
You underestimate me.
不  你低估我了
No, you underestimate me.
這案子可以由聯調局和國際刑警組織聯合調查
This can either be a joint FBI and Interpol case
或由聯調局單獨負責
or just FBI.
決定權在你
Your choice.
我知道這娃娃沒有眼睛
Well, I know it doesn't have eyes,
但我發誓它正盯著我
but I swear it's staring at me.
是啊  這絕對是到現在為止我收到的
Yeah, it's definitely the most unique gift
最特別的禮物
I've gotten so far.
說到禮物...
Well, speaking of gifts...
《我們懷孕了接下來做什么》
"We're pregnant, and now what?"
《如何當個好母親》
"How to not screw up motherhood."
你應該過來給我打氣的  對吧
You were supposed to come over and cheer me up, right?
我是來給你打氣的
I am here to cheer you up.
因為不管生孩子對我來說有多難
Because as hard as having a baby was for me,
老天吶  真的很難
and dear god it was hard,
我缺少一個很重要的部分
there was one big thing I wish I had--
一個伴侶  而彼得是最好的伴侶
A partner, and you have the best kind in Peter.
是啊
Yeah.
我知道
I do, I know.
但孩子發燒的時候他會在這里嗎
But will he be here when I'm trying to get the baby's fever down?
我需要獨自一人去參加所有的
Am I gonna be going to all these parent/teacher
家長會嗎
conferences by myself?
戴安  你別誤會
I mean, Diana, don't get me wrong,
我知道彼得會想做個好父親
I know Peter's gonna love being a dad,
但他的工作需要太多時間精力
but his job is very demanding.
感覺你現在荷爾蒙泛濫了
Sounds like you've got hormones whispering in your ear.
相信我  我經歷過這些
Trust me, I've been there,
但我們說的可是彼得
but this is Peter we're talking about.
他現在能勻出時間陪你
He's gonna dedicate himself to fatherhood
一定也能勻出時間精力陪伴孩子的
like he did the FBI and to you.
-我知道  但...  -沒事的
- I know, but-- - It's gonna be okay.
有了孩子  很多事情都會改變
Having a baby changes everything.
但別讓它改變
Just try not to let it change
你們倆已經擁有的一切
what the two of you already have.
好的
Yeah.
你的清潔工夜班上得如何
How were your adventures in the janitorial night shift?
提醒了我不要用雙手
Oh, a stark reminder that I shouldn't touch doorknobs
碰門把手  還有桌子
with my bare hands, or tables,
或者任何東西
or anything really.
得到你想要的了嗎
You get what we wanted?
我在阿特拉斯科技公司刷了一晚上廁所
I scrubbed toilets at Atlas Tech all night.
這絕不是我想要的
Want had nothing to do with it,
但我的確得到了需要的東西
but I did get what was needed.
艾米的辦公桌就在總裁辦公室外
So Amy's desk sits outside the CEO's office.
走廊盡頭
Down the hallway away from everything else
是一扇鋼筋加固的門
is this steel-reinforced door, which only opens
只能用匹配的指紋和虹膜掃描打開
to the appropriate fingerprint and iris scan.
所以我們需要她幫我們打開門
So we need her to open the door for us.
還得保證她不知情
Without knowing she did it.
一旦我們進入了電腦主機
Once we gain access to the mainframe computer,
就把出埃及記文件拷到這個上面
we just drag and drop the Exodus file onto this.
然后我們就神不知鬼不覺地離開
And then we are in the wind with no one the wiser.
謝謝
Oh, thanks.
清洗馬桶總能讓我食欲大增
Commode cleansing always builds up my appetite.
我不想這么說  但我覺得我們需要凱勒的幫助
I hate to say it, but I think we need Keller for this.
太好了
Great.
到時候他可以幫我看守雞舍
Afterwards I have a henhouse he can guard.
不  彼得說得對
No, Peter was right.
如果我們不合作  就會妨礙彼此
If we don't work together, we'll trip over each other.
那你的計劃是什么
So what's your plan?
你在吃的就是
You're eating it.
既然你不能離開辦公桌去吃午飯
Since you can't leave your desk for lunch,
我就給你帶過來了
I thought I'd bring lunch to you.
尼爾  我真不知道說什么好了
Neal, I-I don't know what to say.
就說你會扔掉
Uh, say that you'll throw away
那盒不知為何物的東西
whatever that is supposed to be.
樂意之至
Happily.
希望我沒有做得太過
I hope I'm not overstepping here.
天吶  你開玩笑吧
Oh, my God, are you kidding?
這個太棒了
This is amazing.
謝天謝地我老板不在
Thank god my boss isn't here.
天吶
Oh, my God.
太好吃了
This is delicious.
真的嗎
You think so?
謝謝你
Thank you.
怎么了
What is it?
是那個家伙
It's--it's that guy
昨天在農貿市場看到的那個
from yesterday from the farmer's market.
你確定嗎
You sure?
應該是
I think so.
我認識這里所有的保安
I know every guard here,
而昨天之前我從沒見過他
and I've not seen that man since before yesterday.
你覺得這是怎么回事
What do you think that means?
不知道
I don't know.
也許你該聯系安保人員
Maybe you should call security.
電話不通  天吶
There's no dial tone. Oh, my God.
他是不是想偷什么東西
What if he's trying to steal something?
你們這是科技公司  對吧
You guys are a tech firm, right?
也不會有什么值錢的東西
It's not like you keep any valuables around.
這可不一定
That's not necessarily true.
他是從保險庫那邊出來的
And he was coming from the vault room.
他不可能進到房間里
There's no way he could have gotten in there.
你想去確認一下嗎
All right, do you want to check?
-我待在這  幫你看著  -謝謝
- I'll stay here, keep an eye out. - Thank you.
我肯定沒什么大不了的
I mean, I'm sure it's nothing.
不  去看看  以防萬一
No, go ahead, make sure.
-謝謝  -沒事
- Thank you. - Yeah.
艾米
Amy.
電話可以用了
The phones are working.
需要我聯系安保部門嗎
You want me to call security?
不用了
No, it's fine.
一切正常
Everything's where it should be.
你好啊  古董
Oh, hello, 1970s.
看來我帶了把激光劍來參加一場持刀搏斗
Looks like I brought a light saber to a knife fight.
這下不妙了
This is not good.
-搞定了嗎  -還沒
- Are we done? - Not yet.
-靠蚊子了  -蚊子是什么
- Mozzie's on it. - What's a mozzie?
他是卡夫瑞的靈魂伴侶
Oh, he's Caffrey's soul mate.
我們還需要一個幫手
We needed a third man.
我不可能找粉紅豹的人來
I wasn't gonna recruit one of the Panthers.
而且  沒有人比蚊子更合適了
Besides, there's no one better than Moz.
不能有秘密  我們說好了的
No secrets. That was our deal.
好了  是你在配合聯調局
All right, look, you're working with the FBI,
不是反過來
not the other way around.
貨車客們  有麻煩了
Van-dwellers, there's a problem.
你拷到文件沒有
Did you copy the file or not?
沒有
I did not.
文件不在嗎
It wasn't there?
有個問題
Well, there's a problem.
問題是這個不能被拷到這個上面
The problem is that this can't be copied onto this.
所以我把原件拿來了
So I took the original.
拿到出埃及記文件的唯一方式
The only way to access the Exodus file
是回到未來
is to go back to the future.
根本不該把這個帶出保險庫
That should have never left the vault.
如果有人發現這東西丟了
If someone discovers this missing,
這次行動就完蛋了
this operation is a bust.
我們把它偷出來
We got it out.
還會把它放回去
We'll get it back in
在提取了"出埃及記"文件之后
after extracting the Exodus File.
祝你們好運
Good luck with that.
IBM在1965年起用鳥類-灰背隼(Merlin)/魚類-鰷魚(Minnow)
人名-格力佛(Gulliver)/地名-馬德里(Madrid)/樂器-短笛(Piccolo)來命名其磁盤驅動器
這是初代"魚盤"
This is a first generation "Minnow" disk,
是1971年的頂尖技術產品
state of the art in 1971.
是的  它是最原始的磁盤存儲工具
Yeah, the primordial ooze of magnetic storage.
能存儲高達八萬字節的文件  以現在的標準看
Holds a whopping 80 kilobytes, which in modern standards
就像用小貨車裝了一窩跳蚤
is like using a minivan to haul a family of fleas.
現在這種老盤早就不銷售了
Now, these early disks were never marketed commercially,
所以你們很難找到驅動器
So you'll be hard pressed to find a drive
來讀取或打開它
that can read it or talk to it.
有讀取工具
Mm, they're out there.
一個高科技公司居然用這種古董
A high tech security firm uses an antique.
-為什么  -冷戰時期的技術
- Why? - Eh, cold war-era tech.
這才是新型防火墻
It's the new firewall.
與以云端技術為基礎的系統和密碼網絡不同
Unlike cloud-based systems and password encoded networks,
它永遠不會被黑
they can't be hacked.
不能聯網  就沒人能黑進去
No internet connections, no espionage.
軍方篤信這種古董
Listen, our military trusts those antiques
能保護核彈的發射命令
to protect the launch commands at nuclear silos.
好吧  我們打印文件
Okay, we print the file.
再利用那姑娘把它放回去
Use the girl to put it back.
不
No.
不  不能再利用艾米了
No, we're not using Amy again.
如果不還回去  她還是會被炒  懂嗎
If it is not returned, she loses as well, no?
他說得有道理
He has a point.
我們不該把她卷進來
Look, she doesn't deserve this.
可你有其他辦法嗎
Well, do you know any other way?
沒有
Oh, not really.
保險庫的安保措施嚴密  我們進不去
I mean, that vault is too secure to break back into.
我不想傷害她
I just don't want to hurt her.
可你如果不那么做  她可能受到更大傷害
Well, she could get hurt worse if you don't.
她以為我是廚師
She thinks I'm a chef.
我今晚會給她做晚餐
I'll make her dinner tonight,
拖住她  直到你們打印完文件
stall her until you've printed out a copy,
然后你把盤帶過來
you bring the disk over...
你分散一下她的注意力
You create a small diversion,
我趁機偷偷把盤放進她包里
and I'll slip it into her purse.
她看到盤在包里會怎么樣
And when she finds it?
她會將盤物歸原位
She puts it back where it belongs.
對嗎  為了自保
Right, to save herself?
可這樣她就會知道是我干的
But she'll know I did it.
就會知道自己被騙了
She'll know she was conned.
有辦法讓她稍稍好受點嗎
Any way to soften the blow?
只能把這頓飯搞成有史以來最乏味約會了
Make this the most uneventful dinner date ever?
-你好寶貝  -你好親愛的
- Hi, hon. - Hey, honey.
盧克  這是我妻子伊麗莎白
Oh, uh, Luc, this is my wife, Elizabeth.
伊麗莎白  這是國際刑警盧克·雷諾
Elizabeth, this is Luc Renaud from Interpol.
就是放跑了綁架我的人的那位
Oh, the man who let my kidnapper go free.
歡迎
Welcome.
祝你好運
Good luck with that.
聽著  蚊子在餐廳
Listen, Mozzie's in the dining room.
他好像又從跳蚤市場小推車上摔下來了
I think he fell off the yard sale wagon again.
晚安
Good night.
為什么在這做而不是聯調局
Why here? Why not the F.B.I.?
法國人和他們的案子
Ah, the French and their inquisitions.
你好  貓咪探員
Hello, suit.
警官
Le suit.
蚊子不肯去聯調局
Uh, Mozzie avoids the F.B.I..
我只在尼爾
I only make an appearance
需要我幫助的時候才出現
when Neal needs my assistance.
警官  為了歡迎你  當然不是專門給你的
Le suit, in your honor, not that you deserve any,
我帶來了一瓶2005年的"德拉維爾酒莊"
I brought a 2005 Chateau De La Vere.
不客氣
You're welcome.
我不喝酒
I do not drink.
什么
I'm sorry?
我不喜歡酒的味道
I don't enjoy the taste.
你做過腦部腫瘤掃描嗎
Have you been scanned for a brain tumor?
這些東西都是怎么弄來的
Do I want to know how you got all this stuff?
可以說是我從
Um, let's just say I borrowed them
某人的私人收藏里借來的
from someone's personal collection.
蚊子
Mozzie.
我給了他一些我的東西作為交換
In exchange for something from mine.
不要再提問了  好嗎
No more questions, okay?
既然我們沒有讀取磁盤的
So, since we don't have all the exact equipment
必要裝備
needed to read the disk,
那么過程中就會伴隨很多嘗試  錯誤  和思考
this will require a lot of trial, error, musing.
讓我們簡化思考過程
Well, let's go easy on the musing.
因為我們想像不到  為了拖住她
We don't know how many courses Neal
尼爾得做多少道菜
has to stall her with.
所以尼爾才讓我
This is why Neal has recruited someone
來冷卻這個過程
to cool down the proceedings.
艾米
Amy, wow.
你看起來...
You look...
很有夏天風范
You look like summer.
又熱又潮濕嗎
Hot and humid?
不  不  光彩照人  請進
No, no, golden. Come in.
為了今晚  我特意借的
I bought it just for tonight.
聞起來真香
Something smells delicious.
是的  我做了魚
Uh, yeah, it's fish.
希望你不會對魚過敏
I hope you're not allergic.
不會  我對什么都不過敏
Oh, no, I can eat anything.
你家
Your place,
天啊  可真漂亮
my God, it's beautiful.
我得給魚翻個面了
I need to turn the fish.
香煎比目魚嗎
Ooh, sole meuniere?
這是真正的歐洲比目魚
It's real sole from Europe.
太平洋的不是真正的比目魚  更接近鰈魚
Pacific is not true sole. It's more of a flounder.
好吧  除了食物你還知道別的什么嗎
Okay, is there anything you don't know about food?
我很樂于學習新知識
I'm always eager to learn something new.
我也是
Me too.
我覺得這會是完美的搭配[一對]
I think this'll be the perfect pairing.
-什么  -酒啊
- What? - The wine.
是啊  對
Oh, right, yes.
這是白蘇維濃葡萄酒
Oh, yes, this is the, uh, Sauvignon Blanc,
產自盧瓦爾河谷
Sancerre from the Loire Valley.
-是啊  -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
酒最好還是用來喝  而不是用來聊
It's better to drink it than talk about it.
沒錯
You're right.
我得切點蔥
Oh, I have leeks to slice.
我一直想學這個
I have always wanted to learn how to do this.
-你能教我嗎  -當然
- Will you show me? - Sure.
秘訣就是握刀的方法
Yeah, the secret is to hold the knife properly.
握住刀柄這里  感受它的重量
Just pinch the hilt here, feel the weight of it.
好吧  這樣嗎
Okay. Like this?
對  這樣  另一只手配合
Yeah, like that, and take with your other hand,
中間三根手指在前
these three fingers, middle and the front,
另外兩根手指在后
the other two behind,
關節抵住刀
And let your knuckle guide the knife,
一點點向前切
and slice going forward.
好吧  看你做要容易得多
Okay, I think this looked a lot easier when you did it.
不  讓刀自然而然地幫你切就行了
No, you just have to let the knife do the work for you.
小心  刀很鋒利
Be careful, it's sharp.
我太笨了
I'm kind of a klutz.
不  沒事  不不不  看到嗎
No, that's okay. No, no, no, see?
手臂不用移動太多
You barely have to move your arm.
一點點向前切就行
Just slice going forward.
就這樣
There you go.
你最好看著蔥
You better keep your eye on the leeks.
-不然會切到手  -抱歉
- You're going to cut yourself. - Oh, sorry.
你們好
Oh, hello, hello.
瓊
June.
希望我沒打擾到你們
I hope I'm not intruding.
沒  沒關系  快進來
No, not at all. Come in.
艾米  這是我的好朋友兼房東  瓊
Amy, this is my good friend and landlady, June.
-瓊  這是艾米  我的客人  -你好
- June, this is Amy... my guest. - Oh, hi.
-你好  艾米  -很高興見到你
- Hello, Amy. - Nice to meet you.
很高興見到你
Nice to see you.
樓上傳來陣陣香味
Those smells were coming up the stairs.
我必須得上來看看尼爾在做什么好吃的
I had to come up to see what is Neal cooking?
尼爾剛在跟我說比目魚的歷史
Neal was just telling me the history of the sole.
是的
Yeah.
香煎比目魚嗎
Sole meuniere?
我最愛吃了
My favorite.
希望你們煎了很多
I hope you've prepared lots.
當然  一向如此
Oh, yes, always.
瓊  我有跟你說過太平洋比目魚
June, have I ever told you the difference
和歐洲比目魚之間的區別嗎
between Pacific and European sole?
沒有
Um, no.
差別可大了
Well, it's fascinating.
歐洲比目魚...
You see, European sole--
又失敗了
Another loser?
讓點地方給我
Give me some room.
另外  噴古龍水是不能代替每天洗澡的
And by the way, cologne is not a substitute for daily bathing.
你可能沒正確裝載磁盤
Maybe you loaded the disk incorrectly.
這又不像是往洗碗機里放盤子
It's not like loading a dishwasher.
更像是為婚禮做座位安排
It's more like making a seating arrangement for a wedding,
把合適的人安排在一起
putting the right people together
這樣他們能互相交談
so that they might actually talk to each other.
好了
Okay.
我成功了
I did it?
I did it.
過時科技  這是現代科技
DOS, meet DOT.
現代科技  這是過時科技
DOT, DOS.
當現代科技和過時科技互相融合...
And when a DOT and a DOS love each other very much...
我好想念這個聲音
Oh, I miss that sound.
就是這個  一定是這個
That's it. It has to be.
我去給尼爾打電話
I'm gonna call Neal.
我們打開文件了
Hey, we opened the file.
現在正在打印
It's printing now.
太好了
Good, good.
瓊巧妙地來當電燈泡了
June threw an excellent block.
太棒了
Terrific.
好了  記住  我到的時候
All right, remember, when I get there,
分散她的注意力
create a diversion.
-彼得  -你說
- Peter. - Yeah.
我挺喜歡她的  我覺得她也喜歡我
I really like her, and I think she likes me too.
當她到家發現磁盤的時候
It's gonna kill her when she gets home
會承受不住的
and discovers that disk.
或許她不會把這事和你聯系到一起
Well, maybe she won't connect it with you.
拜托  她離開家的時候
Come on, when she left her house,
她手上沒磁盤  見了我之后  就有了
she didn't have the disk, and after seeing me, she does?
她還能怎么想
What else could she think?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
好吧
All right.
我錯過了些什么
What'd I miss?
我們之間的小秘密
Uh, nothing we want to share.
我該走了
I better be going.
這么快
Whoa, so soon?
你還沒吃魚呢
Yeah, you haven't had the fish yet.
艾米和我約了要一塊吃早飯
Amy and I are going to have breakfast together.
-真的嗎  -是的
- Really? - Yes.
抱歉  我們不帶你去
Sorry, you're not invited.
太傷心了
Ouch.
-再見  -再見
- Bye. - Bye.
再見
Bye.
你一定餓壞了
You must be starving.
我能等
I could wait.
你確定嗎
You sure?
瓊人很好  對嗎
June's great, isn't she?
她很可愛
She's a lovely lady,
但她走了
but she's gone.
我們還在這
We're still here.
我剛到紐約的時候
You know, when I got to New York,
一無所有
I didn't have anything.
沒地方住  沒衣服穿
No place to stay, no clothes,
她讓我住在這里  直到我...
she let me stay here until I could--
不是我的電話
That's not my phone.
抱歉  是我老板打來的
Sorry, that's my boss's ringtone.
-沒關系  -等一下
- That's okay. - Hang on.
好的
Okay.
稍等一下
Hold that thought.
我必須接這個電話
I have to take this.
格蘭特先生  在倫敦還好嗎
Mr. Grant, how's London?
是嗎
Oh, you are?
什么時候
When?
什么
What?
好的
Yeah.
對  不不不  明天一早
Right, no, no, no, first thing.
我會到的
I'll be there.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
我老板提前回來了
My boss came back early.
保險庫里有件非常重要的東西不見了
There's something very important missing from the vault.
我會被炒魷魚的
I'm gonna be fired.
這到底是什么
What is all this?
可能是個絕密文件
Could be a top secret cryptogram.
我覺得看上去更像是種復雜算法
Looks more like a complex algorithm to me.
他們就希望你這么認為
That's what they want you to believe.
他們
They?
Them.
那個人
The man.
神的右手  "天目"
The Right Hand. The eye in the sky.
聯調局探員們
The suits.
粉紅豹是竊賊團伙
The Pink Panthers are thieves.
你是個怪人
You are a most peculiar man.
時間會證明我是對的
Until I'm right.
我的線人  我的任務
My C.I., my mission.
對你而言這是一個任務
To you it's a mission.
對我而言這是一切
To me it's everything.
尼爾從沒跟你合作過
Neal has never worked with you.
是時候讓他開始與我合作了
It's time he started.
好吧
Okay.
我受夠了
I'm done.
一名探員就夠受的了  兩名探員讓人忍無可忍
Two suits acting like suits is two suits too many.
還有  不客氣
Oh, and again, you're welcome.
艾米的老板提前回來了
Amy's boss came back early.
他知道出埃及記文件不見了
He knows the Exodus file is missing.
他報警了嗎
Has he called the police?
安保公司會承認他們的安保措施不夠嚴密嗎
A security firm admitting that their security is breached?
我覺得不會  除非他們
I doubt it, not until they
想出辦法掩蓋自己的過錯
come up with a way to cover their asses.
解決這個問題要多長時間
How much time to fix this?
需要讓我換上西裝
The time it takes for me to change back into my suit,
跟我太太吻別
kiss my wife good-bye,
再開車去哈羅德·格蘭特家這么久
and drive to Harold Grant's home.
去做什么
To do what?
告訴他真相
Tell him the truth.
作為聯調局調查的一部分  我們拿走了文件
We took the file as part of an FBI investigation.
可能他會合作
Maybe he'll cooperate.
要是他不肯呢
What if he doesn't?
這一切都前功盡棄了嗎
We throw all of this away?
我跟你一樣想要緝拿他們歸案
I want this as much as you do,
但現在我們只能這么做
but this is our only play right now.
那姑娘怎么辦
What about the girl?
她跟這件事毫無關系
She's an innocent in all this.
我會確保她安然無恙的
I'll make sure nothing bad happens to her.
我會給尼爾打電話
I'll call Neal,
讓他送她回家
have him send her home.
馬修  帶上槍
Matthew, grab your gun.
我要你馬上來見我
I need you to meet me.
他為什么會怪你
Why would he blame you?
我的工作就是在他離開時保管好這些東西
It's my job to take care of things while he's away,
我可真是干得不錯
and boy, I sure did a great job,
讓絕密文件從我眼皮底下被偷走了
let a top secret file get stolen from under my nose.
盧克
Luc?
我們走
Let's go.
盧克
Luc?
正在處理  一切都在掌控之中
先不要對格蘭特說  -盧克
從我剛到紐約就一直做這份工作
I've had this job since I first arrived in New York,
六年來我一直試圖晉升
six years trying to move up the ladder.
結果還沒爬上去就先摔下來了
Guess I fell off before I climbed very far.
你見完他之后給我打電話好嗎
Will you call me after you meet with him?
我不希望你獨自承受這一切
I don't want you to go through this alone.
謝謝你
Thank you.
艾米在哪
Where's Amy?
她剛進公寓大門
She just went into her apartment.
盧克把磁盤拿走了
Luc took the disk.
他可能想栽贓給她
He could be trying to plant it on her.
親愛的
Oh, sweetheart,
你應該去洗澡的
you should have climbed into that tub.
我要報警
I'm calling the police.
我可不能讓你這么做
I can't let you do that.
放松  放松
Hey, just relax. Just relax.
放松  好嗎
Just relax, okay?
一切都會   一切都會沒事的
Everything's gonna be--hey. Everything's gonna be just fine.
我們來談談
Let's just talk about--
-等等  你為什么要這么做  -尼爾
- Wait, why are you doing this? - Neal!
她知道是我們偷的  卡夫瑞
She knows we stole it, Caffrey.
等等
Wait.
你們倆認識嗎
You two know each other?
她比我想象的聰明多了
She's smarter than I thought.
他就是個騙子  知道嗎
He's a conman, okay?
你被騙了  不用覺得自己很特別
You've been conned, but don't feel special, all right?
你不是第一個受害者
You're not his first victim.
他騙過的人遍布世界各地
He's done this to people all over the world.
對嗎  小子
Right, kid?
是真的嗎
Is that true?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid it is.
卡夫瑞  我們別無選擇
Caffrey, we're out of options, all right?
我們必須處理好這件事
We need to take care of this.
來吧
Come on.
-別碰我  -放開她
- Don't touch me! - No, get off of her.
你退后  行嗎
Just stay back, all right?
她會幫我們的
She's gonna help us.
我不會幫你們的
I'm not helping you.
我從沒想過要把你卷進來
Look, I never meant to get you into trouble,
但已經這樣了
but I did,
我會幫你脫身的
and I will get you out.
-怎么脫身  -去承認
- How? - By confessing.
承認是你拿了磁盤  不是別人做的
You took the disk, no one else.
我不會承認自己沒做過的事
I'm not confessing to something I didn't do.
你必須去
You have to.
我們為殺手工作  那些人比他還可怕
Look, we work for killers, men worse than him.
他們知道你的住處  你的工作地點
They know where you live, where you work.
不
No.
不  不  你還是想騙我
No, no, you're just still trying to con me.
不是
No.
如果我承認了  我會坐牢的
I confess, I go to jail.
你們兩個倒是逍遙法外了
You two get off scot-free.
你不會坐牢的
You're not going to jail.
你會升職的
You're gonna climb the ladder.
明天一早  你就拿著這個磁盤
Tomorrow morning, you're gonna take this disk
去你老板的辦公室  對他說
into your boss's office and tell him.
格蘭特先生
Mr. Grant,
是我偷了出埃及記文件
I stole the Exodus file.
你忠心耿耿為他工作了六年
You've given him six years of loyalty
沒有得到任何的認可和晉升
with no recognition, no promotions.
每天早上我是第一個到的
I'm the first one here in the morning,
每天晚上最后一個走
and the last to leave at night.
你只把我看做是一個小助理
You see me as an assistant,
從來沒有以別的眼光看待過我
and you've never seen me as anything else.
現在不同了
Now you will.
你偷了這個磁盤  就暴露了
By stealing this disk, you've exposed
這個公司的一個重大安全漏洞
a major security flaw in this company.
你有大麻煩了
You are in serious trouble.
你也一樣
And so are you.
這個漏洞會讓我們的客戶擔憂
This flaw could be troubling for our clients.
如果你連一張磁盤都看不住
If you can't protect a little disk...
最后
Now for the closer.
你提出會守口如瓶
You offer your silence.
他拿回磁盤
He gets the disk back,
誰也不會知道它曾遺失過
no one will ever know it was gone,
作為封口的代價
but in exchange for your silence,
你將會得到你應得的晉升
you get a promotion to the level you deserve.
畢竟  你向他證明了他低估了你
After all, you've proven that he underestimated you.
怎么樣
Well?
我按你說的做了
Well, I did exactly as you said.
然后呢
And?
然后我辭職了
And I quit.
你說什么  他沒提出給你升職嗎
What are you talking about? He didn't offer you a promotion?
為了封住我的口  他什么都愿意做
He would have done anything to keep me quiet.
-那為什么  -我不希望這樣
- Then why-- - I didn't want it that way.
我不會通過利用和控制別人來得到自己想要的
I don't use and manipulate people to get what I want.
我跟你不一樣
I'm not like you.
艾米
Amy-- ooh!
謝謝你
Thank you.
讓我認清了  我并不屬于這個城市
For making me realize I don't belong in this city.
你說得沒錯  這是個算法
You were right. It's an algorithm.
用來計算什么的
What does it calculate?
不是用來計算的  是用來選擇
It doesn't calculate anything. It chooses.
它在變量之間
It draws lines between variables connecting them
任意連線
in a seemingly arbitrary manner.
-就像隨機發生器  -對
- Like a randomizer. - Yeah.
變量都是什么
What are the variables?
變量分三類
There are three categories,
每一類的數量都不同
a different amount of variables in each one.
這是分類一
Here's category one.
DFW  達拉斯沃思堡國際機場
BOS  波士頓洛根國際機場
MSP  明尼阿波利斯圣保羅國際機場
字母DFW  BOS  MSP
Letters DFW, BOS, MSP.
-國際機場  -全都在美國
- International airports. - All of them in the U.S.
這里的則是航空公司和對應的航班號
These right here, airlines and corresponding plane numbers.
都是國際航空公司
International airlines.
不管他們要運輸的是什么
So whatever they're transporting
都是來往于國際之間的
is going in and out of the country.
我們還沒有弄清楚這些數字的含義
We haven't figured out what these numbers mean yet,
但我們認為這些數字一定與
but we think it has something to do
貨物的目的地相對應
with where the shipment ends up.
如果這些都是隨機選擇的
If everything is chosen at random--
沒人知道飛機上是誰或者飛向哪里
No one knows who's flying or where
直到算法做出選擇
until the algorithm chooses.
隱匿得如此之深
Cloaked in this kind of secrecy,
目標的價值一定非常高
it must be a very high value target.
沒有周密的計劃
And without planning,
無法完成這樣的搶劫
it's almost an impossible heist.
除非你掌握了算法
Unless you have the algorithm.
至于這個  多虧尼爾和凱勒
Of which, thanks to Neal and Keller,
粉紅豹現在已經得到算法了
the Pink Panthers do.
干得漂亮  你們倆
Excellent work, you two.
盧克
Luc.
請坐
Have a seat.
你從我家偷走了證據
You stole evidence from my house.
我給國際刑警打了電話想帶你到局里
I called Interpol hoping I could bring you in.
但是當我提起你的名字
When I mentioned your name,
他們的反應就像是我報告說我看到了貓王
they acted like I was reporting an Elvis sighting.
你很生氣  我不明白
You're upset. I don't understand.
正是靠我的線人
Thanks to my C.I.,
伍德福德拿到了出埃及記文件的拷貝
Woodford has a copy of the Exodus file,
而阿特拉斯科技公司也沒有聲張
and Atlas Tech stayed quiet.
這是雙贏啊
Win-win.
你的線人差點殺了一個無辜的女子
Your C.I. Almost killed an innocent girl.
我們倆現在還能保住工作
My C.I.'s the only reason you and I
靠得是我的線人
aren't both mall cops right now.
這又有什么關系呢
Does it matter anymore?
我絕不會拿無辜的生命來冒險
I will not risk an innocent life.
我會不惜一切代價
And I will do whatever is necessary
拿下粉紅豹
to bring down the Panthers.
有我在你就別想
Not on my watch.
那就等你不在的時候
Then when you're not watching.
要不要我現在就以
How about I arrest you right now
妨礙聯調局調查的罪名逮捕你
for interfering with an FBI investigation?
國際刑警說你根本不存在
Interpol said you didn't exist.
我們可以把你關在你不存在的地方
We have places we can put you where you don't.
一巴掌  很有瓊·克勞馥的風采
A slap, very Joan Crawford.
我活該
I deserved it.
我不應該讓艾米涉險的
I never should have put Amy in harm's way.
-你是說凱勒嗎  -或者更糟
- Oh, you mean Keller's way? - Even worse.
沒有更糟的了  也許盧克除外
There is no worse except maybe Luc.
他已經讓我重新考慮要不要那么喜歡法國了
He has me seriously reconsidering my francophilia.
至少現在我們知道
Well, at least now we know he's not afraid
他什么都干得出來
to get his hands dirty.
他是一個不喝紅酒的法國人
Uh, he's a Frenchman who doesn't drink wine.
他還有什么干不出來的
He's capable of anything.
我從沒想過成為這種人  蚊子
I never wanted to be this guy, Moz.
沒想過我會去傷害無辜之人
Someone who hurts innocent people.
騙子的困擾
The conman's quandary.
也許我正因為此才喜歡給聯調局干活
Maybe that's why I like working for the F.B.I.
他們只騙壞人
They only con bad people.
我引用一下W.C.菲爾茲的名言
I still ascribe to W.C. Fields' mantra.
"你無法欺騙正直的人"
"You can't cheat an honest man."
艾米是個例外
Well, Amy was the exception.
她是個好人
She's a good person,
年復一年想要構筑美好的未來
Spent years trying to build her future,
這一切卻毀于我手
and I stole that from her.
你可以換個角度來看這件事
Or you could look at it the other way.
什么角度
What other way?
如果不是你保護她免遭凱勒的加害
If you hadn't been there to protect her from Keller,
她就什么未來都沒有了
she wouldn't have had a future to steal.
親愛的
Honey.
剛來這里嗎  水手
New in town, sailor?
你看起來真性感
You look hot.
-過來  -不行  不行
- Come here. - Oh, no, no, no.
除非你請我去市中心吃一頓奢華晚宴
That's gonna cost you a very expensive dinner downtown.
-這可是周二  -沒錯
- On a Tuesday? - Yes.
我們還有六個月可以隨性而為
We have six months to be spontaneous.
-孩子  -沒錯
- The baby. - Yes.
以后我們要根據孩子來安排時間
It's going to set our schedule,
我在巴布餐廳訂了八點的位子
so we have 8:00 reservations at Babo.
我們可以遲一點
Let's be late.
親愛的
Hey, hon...
我就是在隨性而為
I'm being spontaneous.
你會陪在我們身邊的  對嗎
You're gonna be here for us, right,
我和孩子
me and the baby?
當然了  怎么可能不在
Yeah, why wouldn't I?
我知道你的工作很重要
I know you do important work,
但是身為人父也很重要
but being a father is important too.
這么多年來我都希望能當上爸爸
I've spent years dreaming of being a dad,
我一秒都不想錯過
and I don't want to miss one second of it.
我會陪著你成為一個好媽媽
I am gonna love watching you be a mom.
我們會是好父母的
We're gonna be great parents.
我希望我們不要失去彼此
Let's just not lose this, us,
不要失去我們隔著休斯頓街
what we had when I held up that sign
我拿著牌子  你我相視一笑時
and we smiled at each other
心中的那份感動
across Houston Street.
絕對不會
That is impossible.
那我們就晚點再去好了
Let's be really late.
沒問題
Oh, okay.
下棋呢
Chess, huh?
這確實跟以前一樣
Oh, this is like old times.
別坐
Don't sit.
和我自己下更有挑戰
It's more challenging playing against myself.
是嗎
Is that right?
那為什么叫我來
Then why the call?
艾米
Amy.
闖進她的公寓  拿出你的刀
Breaking into her apartment, going for your knife,
你踩了一條絕對不能踩的底線
it was a very fat line you crossed.
是嗎  那么原諒我  卡夫瑞  我有罪
Yeah, well, forgive me, Caffrey, for I have sinned.
然后呢
What is it, huh?
我的懲罰是什么
What's my penance?
還是老樣子
You being you.
如果你再敢這么做
If you try anything like that again,
我就不客氣了
I throw my grenade.
我也不會客氣  我們同歸于盡
And I throw mine, and we're both dead.
臨界點是什么
So where's the sweet spot?
沒有什么臨界點
I don't need one.
要騙人就一定會有間接傷害  卡夫瑞
Collateral damage is a conman's byproduct, Caffrey.
我們這種人  必然會傷害到身邊的人
See, guys like us, we hurt people around us.
我和你可不是一種人
I'm not a guy like you.
你就繼續騙自己吧  甜心
You keep telling yourself that, sweetheart.
你都計劃好了嗎
So what, you got it all figured out?
鏟除粉紅豹  獲得自由  然后呢
Take down the Panthers, we get our freedom, and then what?
幸福美滿地生活下去
We live happily ever after?
差不多吧
Yeah, something like that.
差不多
Something like that.
現實可不是童話  卡夫瑞
Yeah, you're living in a fairy tale, Caffrey.
不管發生了什么  你和我
No matter what happens, me and you,
我們是無法得到平靜的
we're hunted men.
就算我們鏟除了伍德福德和他的團伙
We take down Woodford and his crew,
這一切也不會就這么結束
it's never over.
即使在監獄里  他們還是會設法找我們
Even in prison they'll come looking for us.
而他們  我的朋友  可沒有
And their reach, my friend, it is far,
他們查不到的事
and it is wide.
而粉紅豹  尼爾  他們會至死追查
And the Panthers, Neal, they don't stop looking for rats
出賣他們的人
until they're dead.
到那時  你猜他們會找誰的麻煩
Until then, guess who they go after.
和你最親近的人
People closest to you.
他們不會手下留情的  卡夫瑞
And they make it hurt, Caffrey.
他們下手會重到
They make it hurt so bad
你希望他們找到的是你
that you'll wish that they found you.
你好好享受你來之不易的自由吧
So you enjoy this freedom you're working so hard to get.
因為當你重獲自由之時
Because when you're footloose and fancy free,
你深愛的那些人
those people that you love so much,
離死也就不遠了
they are on death roll.